# **Kevan Barter**

kcbarter@msn.com (360) 402-9986 kcbarter.github.io/kevanbarterportfolio/ www.linkedin.com/in/KevanBarter https://github.com/kcbarter

## **Summary**

Software Engineer experienced in developing full-stack web applications, specializing in Java, TypeScript, and ReactJS. Possessing a strong background in TDD, Agile methodologies, and testing frameworks. Ready to contribute to your team with my diverse skillset and excited to take on new challenges.

#### **Skills**

- Java, Typescript, JavaScript, Git, HTML, Tailwind CSS, SQL, MongoDB, CSS, SCSS, Python, C#, Node
- Springboot, ReactJS, Redux Toolkit, Thymeleaf, Gradle, Android Development, REST, HTTP protocol, Axios API
- TDD, Agile Methodologies, Unit Testing, CI/CD, Playwright, Selenium, JUnit, Jest

# **Professional Experience**

Chenega Agile Real-Time Solutions | Software Engineer | Remote/Hybrid

Feb 2024 - Present

- Develop and maintain responsive web applications using ReactJS and Typescript.
- Implement efficient state management with Redux Toolkit for scalable data flow.
- Utilize Tailwind CSS for modern and visually appealing user interfaces.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to understand project requirements and provide technical insights.
- Contribute to the agile development processes through code reviews and continues integration/continuous development.
- Utilized GitHub version control to keep feature branches up to date and make daily commits.

## Maximus | Software Engineer | Remote/Hybrid

Dec 2023 - Jan 2023

- Assisted in developing and maintaining responsive web applications using ReactJS, Typescript, and TailwindCSS.
- Contributed to fetching data with GraphQL requests for efficient data retrieval and management.
- Supported agile development processes through participation in code reviews, version control using GitHub, and collaboration with senior developers.

#### Microsoft | Software Engineer in Test | Remote/Hybrid

Sep 2022 - Dec 2023

- Migrated testing suite from Selenium to Playwright for Teams app.
- Tackled a very tough problem with legacy code and successfully came up with a strategy to bridge it to new code without any disruption of the business flow.
- Collaborated with developers, PMs, and designers to identify and resolve issues in a timely manner.

## **Projects**

Nitrouz Studioz | Software Engineer | GitHub

Jun 2019 – Present

- Developing a web application for users to create accounts and post in a forum type setting using Java, Spring Boot, SCSS, Thymeleaf, JavaScript, and SQL.
- Followed the MVC design pattern to better separate the project implementation and organized the SQL database so that the SQL tables were normalized.
- Created Model classes to represent SQL data and Controller classes that contained CRUD methods to manipulate/read from the database.

#### Education

Master of Science in Computer Science, Northeastern University
Bachelor of Applied Science in Software Development, Green River College

Jan 2021 to Aug 2022 Sep 2016 to Jun 2019